Actually slight change in plan.
계획이 약간 변경됐어요
I'm going to wrap up the day.
오늘은 이만 퇴근할게요
Day three at this point, and say that we'll take day four to look at the results in weights and biases,
사흘째인데요 나흘째에는 무게와 편향성 결과를 살펴보고 훈련 과정을 검토할
and to examine the progress of training, because I think that we should let it run for a bit and then
겁니다 비트를 좀 더 달리게 한 다음 진지하게 시간을 들여야
take some, some serious time to do that.
할 것 같아요
Um, I'll also at that point be able to show you the model in the Huggingface hub.
어깅페이스 허브에 있는 모델도 보여드릴 수 있어요
And I also I do I feel like I might have been a bit glib about the amount of money that it costs to
그리고 제가 좀 비트를 탄 것 같아요 모델 훈련에 드는 비용에
train these models.
대해서요
I want to be clear that you really don't need to spend any material amount of money for for to have
이 코스를 즐기기 위해 많은 돈을 쓰실 필요는 없어요
a lot of fun with this and investigate hyperparameter optimization as part of this course, it would
하이퍼파라미터 최적화를 살펴보기 위해서요 단돈 몇 센트예요
Um, and so I want to quickly explain how you can do things like reduce your training data set to a
훈련 데이터 세트를 관리하기 쉬운 크기로 줄이는 방법을 간단히
more manageable size, and have more sensible parameters so that you could train on a, um, a normal
설명하고 싶어요 더 합리적인 매개 변수를 만들어 일반 사양 GPU 박스로 훈련하고
spec GPU box and be spending only a few cents on this project.
이 프로젝트에 적은 돈을 쓸 수 있도록요
That's that's all that's required if you wish to be a complete nerd like me and go all out and run lots
저처럼 완전히 괴짜가 되고 싶다면 필요한 건 그게 다예요. 최고급 박스로
of runs with top end boxes and spend 5 or $10 then then, uh, on your head, be it as it will be on
많은 게임을 하고 5달러나 10달러만 쓰면 당신도 당신도 그렇게 될 거예요. 저처럼 말이에요.
But it's not necessary at all.
그럴 필요 없어요
But you do need absolutely to take a moment to congratulate yourself on where you've got to.
하지만 앞으로의 일을 축하하려면 잠시 시간을 가져야 해요
You have a training run happening.
훈련 중이에요
I do hope right now while while I speak it is running.
제가 말하는 동안에 작동하면 좋겠네요
And you are in a position now that you can explain.
이제 설명할 수 있는 위치에 있잖아요
Q Laura pretty well for fine tuning open source models.
오픈 소스 모델을 잘 조정했어요
You're so fed up with me talking about target modules, I'm sure, uh, and now, uh, explaining things
목표 모듈에 대해 얘기하는 데 질리셨을 거예요 학습율이나 알파,
like learning rates, uh, ah and alpha, uh, and uh, dropout and all of the various other things
드롭아웃 같은 걸 설명하는 데도요 최적화 장치 같은 다양한 것들도요 그게
like optimizers and the like, it's all second nature to you, and it's all complex stuff.
다 여러분에게 제2의 본성이자 복잡한 거죠
This is, uh, upskilling in a big way.
이건 정말 큰 활력소예요
So congratulations.
축하해요
It's tremendous progress.
엄청난 발전이에요
And next time we'll go over to weights and biases and see what's happening.
다음 시간에는 무게와 편향으로 가서 어떻게 되는지 보죠